Muhammad Bilal Imrani

Senior Software Engineer

CONTACT INFO

≥ bimrani816@gmail.com

+92 315 6745522

Lahore, Pakistan

in linkedin.com/in/bilal-imrani-722281103/

https://github.com/bilalimrani

EDUCATION

Islamia University Bahawalpur

BS Computer Science Completed in 2016

SKILLS

- JavaScript/TypeScript
- React, Redux, NextJS
- Angular
- AWS (S3, EC2, Route 53, Cloudfront)
- NodeJS, NestJS, ExpressJS
- MongoDB
- GraphQL, Apollo.
- HTML, CSS
- Bootstrap, MUI, Styled Components, TailwindCSS, Ant Design.

CERTIFICATION

Verified International Academic Qualifications

Verified by Credly

Provider:

World Education Services

Issued:

August 2021

PROFILE SUMMARY

Software Engineer having 5+ years of overall experience in web development using ReactJS, Angular, NodeJS, Amazon Web Services, SQL/NoSQL databases, and third-party integrations Experience in application analysis, design, development, maintenance, tuning and debugging Having expertise in problem solving, client communication, team management, and collaboration with other teams

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Systems Limited | Senior Software Engineer

May 2021 - Present

Responsibilities

- Analyze, design and develop complex frontend systems to fit client and business requirements.
- Oversee frontend development, maintain and merge code from team members
- Analyze the system for possible business solutions/bugs/upgrades
- Coordinate with back-end team and assist frontend team members **Environment:** ReactJS, Redux, GraphQL, NodeJS, MongoDB, AWS Services

Applications

Application: (TAMM, a comprehensive single point access portal for all Abu Dhabi government services)

- Worked as a Full Stack developer from April 2021 to February 2022
- Developed TAMM services and tools for Industrial Business Journey.
- Developed REST APIs using ExpressJS and created documentation using Swagger

Environment:

- Technologies: ExpressJS (TypeScript), Camunda, ReactJS (Custom DLS), Git
- Development Tools: VS Code, GitLab, Jira, Camunda Modeler and Cockpit

NorthBay Solutions | Senior Software Engineer

August 2018 - April 2021

Responsibilities

- Analyze, design, & develop complex frontend systems to fit client and business requirements
- Deploy front on AWS
- Analyze the system for possible business solutions/bugs/upgrades **Environment:** ReactJS, Redux, GraphQL, NodeJS, MongoDB, AWS Services

Applications

Application: (Intelligize app used by hundreds of customers)

- Integrated stripe payment processing system
- Integrated GTM for analytics and Klaviyo for tracking users' behavior

Environment: ReactJS, Redux, AWS, Git

CrewLogix | Senior Software Engineer

September 2016 - March 2018

Responsibilities

- Analyze, design, and develop complex frontend systems to fit client and business requirements
- Manage GitHub repositories including maintaining README files
- Coordinate with back-end team and assist frontend team members

Environment: ReactJS, Redux, Angular, NodeJS(Express) MUI, Amazon Web Services